<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>hella labs - Family</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://www.qrk.us/feeds/family.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://www.qrk.us/</id><updated>2025-11-29T05:12:04.117879+00:00</updated><subtitle>helpful findings and tech musings</subtitle><entry><title>A Life in the Twentieth Century: The Memoir of Iris Jean Yandle Beatty</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/a-life-in-the-twentieth-century-the-memoir-of-iris-jean-yandle-beatty.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2006-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-29T05:12:04.117879+00:00</updated><author><name>Iris Jean Yandle Beatty</name></author><id>tag:www.qrk.us,2006-12-08:/a-life-in-the-twentieth-century-the-memoir-of-iris-jean-yandle-beatty.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly an elderly lady, and at the age of seventy-five I decided to do something a lot of old folks do—think about, and then write about, events my family and I have lived through, with hints of the experiences that were delightful, or those that were …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am truly an elderly lady, and at the age of seventy-five I decided to do something a lot of old folks do—think about, and then write about, events my family and I have lived through, with hints of the experiences that were delightful, or those that were harder to manage, or to overcome, or just to live through. Over the seventy-five years of my life there have been sad, glad, terrible, and marvelous, and sometimes even blessed changes in the way all people live, and move, and have their being. When I was born in 1931 the medical community—that is hospitals, doctors, nurses, and makers of medications—had few medicines to offer to patients. There were palliatives, and life-saving surgeries, but not much at all that could truly be called medicines, as we think of them in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-unexpected-arrival"&gt;The Unexpected Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was born in 1931. I was not the first child in our small family. My sister, Ella Cornelia, was born in November, six full years and a few months earlier than me. In those days different families had different rules about explaining to “innocent” children that a child was on the way. My sister was well into her seventh year. In February of 1931 our mother arranged it with a neighbor to “invite” little Ella Cornelia to her house for a day or so, and it happened just like that. Innocent, and unwarned Ella Cornelia went with Pauline Funderburk to her house for an overnight stay, and was having a lovely time when Pauline told her to get ready to go back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister had been the only—not just the only, but the ONLY—grandchild in the Yandle family, and in the Park’s family she was the oldest grandchild. She had been the star of the show for six, going a couple of months into the seventh year, being the star of the show with aunts, uncles, grandparents, cousins, and friends. She in no way expected even the slightest competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ella Cornelia walked confidently into her own house, and didn’t at all understand why her mother was sitting down holding a little baby girl, with several neighbors sitting around the room, all of them paying no attention to Ella Cornelia, who was the only child in the family, and instead watching her as she beheld the fact—and it seemed to be a fact—that Mother was holding a little baby. Since I was so young I can’t offer a quote of just how I was introduced to my sister, but I heard several reports of what my sister squalled out when she actually understood that she had a baby sister. Her first, and for a long time her only unrequited wish was: “Take her back!!!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ella Cornelia (named for Grandmother Ella Yandle, and Grandmother Cornelia Parks so that she was accustomed to hearing her entire name as neither grandmother could be slighted just to shorten her name) was angry that her parents would actually “buy” another baby without at least warning her. She—at seven years old and happy as an only child—most definitely didn’t want a new sister who would share her very satisfactory world. It took about ten or eleven years for my sister to come to grips with the fact that Mother and Daddy were not going to “return” me to where I came from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sisters-illness"&gt;Sister's Illness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn’t help my sister at all that when I was two, or close to three years old, she became seriously ill. Those were days, nearly fifteen years away from penicillin, when there were no sure medications. Medicine, in those days, was mostly helpful in surgeries, injuries, and the birth of children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year was 1933 or 1934. Our mother blamed the illness on intense exertion when playing games with schoolmates. In those days when there was no television, and few radios, children actually went out into the yard and played together. One day the teacher of my sister’s class handed her female students a long jump rope, and they went outside to play during recess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister was a determined person, and she was a pretty good athlete. On that particular day my sister’s group became the jumpers. All of her team-mates touched the rope, however, she was the last surviving jumper in her group. The rules were, that when only one member of a team was still jumping, she could restore her group as jumpers instead of their becoming the rope turners if—and it was a big if—the last jumper still jumping in the game could successfully jump ten turns of the rope alone without touching the rope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister jumped ten turns of the rope by herself, and won another chance for her team. Her team rejoined her, and the game continued. Her team jumped rope for ten games. She had no rest, and she jumped every turn of the rope until she was the only jumper left, then she jumped ten times without touching the rope and won the return of all of her team mates. Ella Cornelia was very proud of herself that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night she developed a fever. It turned into pleurisy and heart trouble. Because her illness was both quick and deadly, at least five doctors at Presbyterian Hospital in Charlotte, North Carolina, examined her. Four of those doctors said that in their opinion there was no hope of her recovery, and it would be better to keep Ella Cornelia as comfortable as possible until she died, because she would never again be really well and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear, dependable Dr. John R. Ashe said she would recover. It was brave of him, because in those days there were no effective antibiotics. He did not give up, and kept treating my sister with strength and courage. She spent a year in bed or a wheelchair, frail and weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Ella Cornelia was ill, and during her recovery, I was actually quite healthy. Because I was healthy, and my sister needed constant nursing and attention, I was farmed out, mostly to my mother’s sister, Ola Davis, who had no children of her own. My mother felt I would be safe with Aunt Ola while she gave all her attention to Ella Cornelia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="family-sketches"&gt;Family Sketches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, my aunt Helen, as a teenager, about seventeen years old, had an illness, and her doctor told her family there was no cure, but if they were willing to try a potion he had been testing, he would treat her. He brought out his concoction that contained an acid that ate her teeth—all of them. She lived, but her teeth had to be pulled, and so she wore false teeth for the balance of her life, from her late teenage years to several years past her ninetieth birthday. Losing her teeth made her more shy than she might have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncle Eddie, my Dad’s older brother, didn’t resemble my Dad at all. By the time that I came along and was old enough to notice people, I wondered why my Dad was over six feet tall, and Uncle Eddie was not even as tall as Aunt Helen. He was thin, and looked frail. He had few teeth, smoked cigarettes, and on Sundays when we came to visit, spent the entire day near the kitchen stove in the winter, and in summer would sit on the porch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes Uncle Eddie would spend part of Sunday afternoon keeping company with the man who ran a gasoline station literally “next door” to the Yandle house. The owner also had cold drinks and candy and chips for sale. I loved to go to the “filling station” where they had ice cream on sticks or in small paper bowls with tops. There were cold drinks like coca colas, Pepsi colas, Seven-ups and grape drinks in a bottle. I loved to get a snack and a drink, and there was a wonderful one when I was very young called a three center (which meant that it cost only three cents, and was sort of a poor man’s coke-a-cola).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Grandmother was a small woman, and I always thought of her as being frail. She birthed at least six children that I know about. One of the illnesses was called eyeritis, and it was inflammation within the eye, and it can cause blindness. That was what happened to my grandmother, and because she was already quite frail, she was never able to attend to the work needed in the kitchen, nor could she see well enough to move around in the house. She remained an invalid for the rest of her life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="early-childhood-on-east-fifth-street"&gt;Early Childhood on East Fifth Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My earliest memories are of the house on East Fifth Street in Charlotte, where we lived until I was about three. It was a duplex across the street from the house owned by my Great-Uncle Edward and Great-Aunt Lizzie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two vivid memories from that time. One is of terror: I wandered into a small back vestibule that had no light, and the door closed behind me, trapping me in pitch darkness until my sister rescued me. The other is of beauty: sitting on the front porch floor, playing with bright crescents of sunlight cast through the arched drainage holes in the solid porch banister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Aunt Lizzie and Uncle Edward Yandle were, in my estimation at the age of five or six, two of the strangest folks I had every met. Neither of them resembled either of my grandparents. They didn’t look like either of my parents, and they behaved differently from any other aunts and uncles. Aunt Lizzie was terrified of germs; she would never touch a doorknob with her bare hand, always using her apron as a shield. Their house had both electric and gas lights—a marvel to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother told me a story about living there when my sister, Ella Cornelia, was a baby. Mother put her in a high chair on the back porch while she hung laundry in the yard. She heard the baby cooing and laughing and thought she was happily entertaining herself. When Mother returned, she found that she had placed the high chair within reach of Aunt Lizzie's prized fern. Ella Cornelia had stripped the fronds, watching the leaves drift down like green snowflakes. Mother never said what Aunt Lizzie’s reaction was, but I imagine it wasn't mild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="life-on-west-eleventh-street"&gt;Life on West Eleventh Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was probably close to three years old when our family moved to Eleventh Street where we lived in a two story duplex with six rooms in each side of the house—three downstairs (Living room, dining room and kitchen) and three bedrooms and a bathroom upstairs. The two dwellings were under one roof, and there was a shared wall which separated the two attached houses. In those days it was possible—not against the law—to rent out the upstairs of a house even though it meant that the downstairs folks had to share the bathroom with the upstairs folks, and the upstairs folks didn’t actually have a kitchen, and had to wash their dishes in the lavatory in the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was about thirteen our upstairs folks who had rented all three rooms of the upstairs left the house and things were re-arranged. Mother and Daddy then placed twin beds in the third upstairs room and my sister and I had a bedroom to ourselves. I was so happy to have a room of our own, and I decided that the dingy walls needed to be refreshed, and one day talked my Dad into giving me a bucket of paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="roots-and-ancestry"&gt;Roots and Ancestry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My forebears were, most certainly, brave. A large number of my ancestors came to the United States from England in the mid-1800s, crossing the Atlantic in small sailing ships. There were two prominent families: the Yandles and the Johnstons. They intermarried frequently—Johnstons marrying Yandles and Yandles marrying Johnstons—and settled in the Carolinas, mostly around Pineville and Fort Mill, or across the Catawba River near Mount Holly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Great-Grandfather Yandle was a storekeeper near Pineville. During the Civil War, when the wives and children of Confederate soldiers had no money for food, he could not bear to turn them away. He would say, "Well, I SAID they needed to eat!" and give them food from his store. Eventually, his generosity caused his bankruptcy, and his younger brother, Edward Yandle, helped him settle his debts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grandfather and his second wife celebrated their Fiftith wedding anniversary when my father was a young lad. My dad and all the youths who were still considered “children” were warned that since there was only one dining table available, the special meal would have to be served one table at a time, with guests taking turns according to age. Therefore the young boys would be last at the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungry and bored, my father and his cousins found a box of cigars that had been a gift to Grandfather. They snitched one, went behind the barn, and took turns puffing on it. It made them all deathly sick. When they were finally called to the feast, the servers were baffled because these usually ravenous boys simply picked at their food. My Dad never smoked again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a sadness in the family that was rarely spoken of. My Dad was the youngest boy, but he wasn't the youngest child. He once mentioned a sister named Stella who died as a toddler. He said only that she was a "beautiful child." I never knew she existed until I found a chipped gravestone in a storage shed on the farm. It read "Stella Yandle." In those days, doctors often couldn't help, and families just had to bear the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-war-years"&gt;The War Years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World War II changed everything. Germany had declared war on most of Europe, and on England. Radios had been available for several years, and most people had at least one. In Europe, Adolph Hitler, who had taken over the government of Germany, started a war in Europe. After that conflict was raging in Europe, the Japanese, half a world away from the United States, but already at war with China, decided to destroy the navy of the United States to prevent our country from interfering in the Pacific battles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They sent their air force to drop bombs on the American ships anchored and stationed in Hawaii, and they tried to destroy the planes of the Army Air Force stationed in Hawaii, as well. Their surprise attack was, from the Japanese viewpoint, quite successful. They sank the navy ships in the harbor, and bombed the airfield. But that was only the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was ten when Pearl Harbor was bombed. Suddenly, there were shortages of sugar, shoes, and gasoline. My father worked away from home for weeks at a time, painting oil tanks in Savannah and other coastal cities. My Dad actually "invented" a device for that work. The huge oil tanks had floating tops that moved up and down with the oil level to prevent fumes from gathering. Dad created a rig that allowed a painter to move horizontally around the tank, then lower the board and go around again. It was dangerous work—a spark could cause an explosion—but he was proud of his solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister worked as a nurse's aide and later in a doctor's office. Toward the end of the war, we learned that German prisoners of war were being kept in camps in the US and sometimes "loaned" to farmers. My sister eventually met and married Harry May, who was one of the Army guards watching over these German POWs on a local dairy farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember the polio epidemic one summer. Schools closed early, and children were confined to their yards. I couldn't go to the library or the movies. It was a lonely time. That was also the summer of my orthodontic ordeal. My teeth had grown in crooked—my "eye teeth" stuck out like tusks. My parents, despite the cost, sent me to one of the few orthodontists in Charlotte. The treatment took eight years. At one point, after four years of little progress, the doctor convinced my Dad (who distrusted doctors after what happened to his sisters) to let him pull four teeth. Finally, the braces came off. I walked home that day weeping with joy, smiling at everyone I passed, grateful to look "normal" at last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="meeting-paw-paw"&gt;Meeting Paw-Paw&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After college, I took a job as church secretary at Calvary Methodist Church. On my very first Sunday there, I met a young man named Robert "Bobby" Beatty. He was the great-grandson of the church's founders. We began dating in December, got engaged on Christmas Eve, and were married in June 1954.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bobby had grown up in Charlotte, too. His grandfather had been a policeman who died at his desk. During the war, Bobby—who was called "Paw-paw" later in life—had to change schools when his family moved in with his grandmother on South Boulevard. His grandmother, "Nan-naw," ran a boarding house for Lance Packing Company workers, preparing lunches and providing beds. Living there, Bobby got to see his cousins more often, as his Aunt Virginia had three sons who lived nearby. He had served in the Army Air Force in the Pacific during the war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reflections"&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now seventy-five years old. My husband is eighty. We have lived through horse-and-buggy days to see men walk on the moon. We have seen the discovery of penicillin, the end of polio, and the invention of television and computers. Life has been full of changes, some sad, some wonderful. I have tried to put down these memories so that my children, Louise and Fred, and my grandchildren will know where they came from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iris Jean Yandle Beatty&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-note-from-ken"&gt;A Note from Ken&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recovered these fragments of Mimi's memoir from her old computer, preserving them alongside audio recordings from my time at her home on Autumnvale Drive, circa 2008. It is a privilege to share these memories with those who knew her. She loved me dearly, as I did her, and I miss her deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; background: #000;"&gt;
    &lt;iframe 
        src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AM_2mmyq3wI" 
        style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 0;" 
        allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" 
        allowfullscreen 
        title="Iris Jean Yandle Beatty Memoir"&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Family"/><category term="memoir"/><category term="family"/><category term="history"/><category term="Charlotte"/></entry><entry><title>The Story of Minnie Brantley</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/the-story-of-minnie-brantley.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2004-10-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-29T05:12:04.117879+00:00</updated><author><name>Iris Jean Yandle Beatty</name></author><id>tag:www.qrk.us,2004-10-12:/the-story-of-minnie-brantley.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note on the Relationship to the Author:&lt;/em&gt;
This narrative appears to be a piece of fiction or a creative writing exercise authored by Iris Jean Yandle Beatty. While the protagonist shares the first name of Iris's mother (Minnie), the life events described—being orphaned at age four, having multiple husbands …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note on the Relationship to the Author:&lt;/em&gt;
This narrative appears to be a piece of fiction or a creative writing exercise authored by Iris Jean Yandle Beatty. While the protagonist shares the first name of Iris's mother (Minnie), the life events described—being orphaned at age four, having multiple husbands, and having no surviving children—contradict the actual biography of Iris's mother, Minnie Parks Yandle, as detailed in Iris's memoirs. Minnie Brantley is a character created by the author, perhaps exploring themes of resilience, loss, and new beginnings that mirrored her own family's values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-i-the-ending"&gt;Part I: The Ending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this significant day, fair skies with high cumulous clouds had blessed the countryside, offering slowly moving areas of shade for the house and the wide yard that was shaded with ten huge oaks, most of them planted a hundred years ago. Toward evening, the breeze that had offered its cooling efforts diminished; however, a brilliant sunset colored the western horizon, as if even the heavens were offering a special finale for this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnie, a middle-aged but sturdy woman, watched her last guest leave, and at last sat down in the swing at the end of the porch, where she could see the western sky as the sunset faded and the daylight dimmed to dusk. The house, almost enwrapped by the great oak trees, was painted white, with screened porches on three sides. Minnie had lived here for twelve years, and she had always enjoyed the wide yards and the big trees. Now she sat alone and quietly in the gently moving swing. It had been a demanding day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the day of Elmer Brantley's funeral. Elmer was Minnie's husband of nearly fifteen years, the fourth generation of his family to farm the land in Parker's Valley. He had died after a grueling illness during which Minnie served as his nurse and the sole manager of the farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnie felt a large sadness at having to leave this house. When she had moved in, she thought she would probably live here for the rest of her life—but she had thought that before. Disappointment had come this time with the same shock and helpless grief she had endured so many times before. She had worked hard to improve the farm and keep it ready for the next generation of Elmer’s family to take it over. But Elmer’s surviving children—three daughters who married military men and moved away, and one son, Clyde—did not want to keep the farm. They want to sell the land and divide the proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-trouble-with-clyde"&gt;The Trouble with Clyde&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most immediate threat was Elmer's son, Clyde. Unlike his father, Clyde was irresponsible and struggled with alcoholism. He had lost his own property and failed to support his wife and five children. Elmer had planned to leave the farm to his only living son, but it had become abundantly clear that Clyde could not handle the farm without losing it or ruining it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night of the funeral, after the guests had left, the silence was shattered. Minnie’s best friends and neighbors, Ardie and Gary, were still with her when they saw headlights turn into the drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think it’s Clyde, headed this way," Gary said. "I saw his truck turn out of his driveway just after I passed it. He couldn’t keep up with me, but he was driving this direction."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clyde’s truck, with one headlight aiming askew, roared up the driveway. He failed to slow appropriately and hit one of the oak trees before coming to a stop. He was staggering drunk. He crawled out of the truck and stumbled onto the porch, yelling for Minnie, pounding on the door until he ripped the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnie stood in the hall, watching through the window as Clyde tried to force the door with a ring of keys that hadn't worked in fifteen years. When that failed, he began to kick the door, screaming in rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I will not live in danger of being attacked or even have my peace disturbed by a drunk every time he takes a notion to call on me," Minnie declared. She called the Sheriff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the deputy arrived, Clyde was cuffed and placed in the backseat of the patrol car. Minnie made the difficult decision to press charges, hoping that jail time and forced rehabilitation might save his life, even if she cannot save his inheritance. She promised to help his wife and children, but she would not hand the farm over to be squandered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-ii-a-history-of-loss"&gt;Part II: A History of Loss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnie's resilience was born of a lifetime of tragedy. As she sat on the porch that night, she reflected on her history of "new beginnings," almost all of which were forced upon her by loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had been orphaned at the age of four. Her parents, a wealthy young couple, died in a car accident while she was staying with a temporary babysitter. Due to a miscommunication, authorities did not know where she was. She spent nearly a year living in poverty with the babysitter's relative, an eccentric elderly woman named "Aunt Hattie."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aunt Hattie lived in a primitive farmhouse without electricity or running water. It was there that Minnie learned to work hard. She went barefoot, wore shirts over her short dresses, and learned to milk cows, chop kindling, and gather eggs. She learned that "they will come when they want to come," a phrase Aunt Hattie used to dismiss her questions about her parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was finally located by her parents' estate lawyers only by accident, when a searcher stumbled upon the connection. Minnie was taken away from the only stability she had found since her parents' death, moving through a series of guardians and caretakers until she came of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adulthood brought its own sorrows—the loss of three husbands and her own children. She learned that "new beginnings" were a skill she had to master to survive. And now, she was facing another one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-iii-the-departure"&gt;Part III: The Departure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determined not to watch Elmer’s farm fall into ruin or be sold to strangers while she was present, Minnie executed a meticulous plan to close down her life there. She gave herself two full months to make preparations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She spent months harvesting the final crops and selling off the beef cattle and pigs. She found homes for the barn cats and cleaned the barns and chicken coops until they were spotless. She packed only her personal belongings and the furniture she bought herself, leaving the rest for Elmer's daughters to claim or sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minnie decided to return to a piece of land she inherited from her parents—500 acres she hasn't seen since she was a child. It had been leased to a paper company for timber, but the lease had expired. She hoped the old house was still standing. She wasn't sure if it was habitable, or even if there was a road to it, but it was hers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="part-iv-the-caravan"&gt;Part IV: The Caravan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bold move, Minnie convinced her best friends, Ardie and Gary, to join her. They, too, were ready for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a Tuesday morning in November, a caravan departed the Brantley farm. Minnie drove a new van pulling a trailer filled with chickens, goats, and pets. Ardie and Gary followed in a moving van, and their sons drove pickup trucks loaded with equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They left behind the sorrow of the past years, heading toward a property Minnie barely remembered, ready to build a new life together from the ground up. It was the sixth—or perhaps seventh—new beginning of Minnie Brantley's life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Family"/><category term="fiction"/><category term="family"/><category term="resilience"/></entry></feed>