<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>hella labs - Gardening</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.qrk.us/feeds/gardening.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.qrk.us/</id><updated>2024-07-27T23:32:18+00:00</updated><subtitle>helpful findings and tech musings</subtitle><entry><title>You can cook dirt?</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/cooking-dirt.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-27T23:32:18+00:00</updated><author><name>Kenneth</name></author><id>tag:www.qrk.us,2024-07-27:/cooking-dirt.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For me, food was always an afterthought. "Ugh. Hungry again. I'll solve that and get back to what I was doing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I read this book from the 70s by a Japanese farmer who's like the grandfather of permaculture. I wish I could have met him. His name was Masanobu …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For me, food was always an afterthought. "Ugh. Hungry again. I'll solve that and get back to what I was doing."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I read this book from the 70s by a Japanese farmer who's like the grandfather of permaculture. I wish I could have met him. His name was Masanobu Fukuoka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fukuoka-san was walking and noticed rice growing wild. It was thriving. He wondered how much he could grow that way without flooding the paddy or starting seedlings. He soon learned he could yield just as much with less effort, and that was just the beginning. He found all sorts of clever ways to avoid industrializing his farm by paying attention to how things work. He was a hacker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called it "do nothing farming." I live in a different climate with different soil. I probably won't be growing buckwheat or rice, but I can apply his philosophy of paying attention and harmonizing instead of dominating the life around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured, "I'm going to need a bunch of dirt." Not soil, per se, but compost as fertilizer. The soil is dense clay here. It doesn't absorb water well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can actually cook dirt. Well, you can "cook" organic matter by composting it, which is to intentionally accelerate decomposition while eliminating odors and weed seeds and other unwanted things. There's more too it than I'd imagined, but not too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I'm Farmer Bingham now, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've a few hundred gallons of matter cooking down to teensy pieces out back. I've selected a patch of ground for planting and smothered what was growing there with plastic so I can enrich the soil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon I'll be amending that bed with my compost and starting some veggies and fruits from seed. There's a lot to know. I made some farmer friends and I'm  hunting for a scobe so I can ferment kombucha. My collection of bottles  for that is growing. I'm hoping to branch out into yoghurt and pickles and kraut too. I love that stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Gardening"></category><category term="composting"></category></entry><entry><title>Monthly Plan</title><link href="https://www.qrk.us/monthly-plan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-27T23:32:18+00:00</updated><author><name>Kenneth</name></author><id>tag:www.qrk.us,2024-07-27:/monthly-plan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the plot" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/41ff140f-d3be-435f-98ca-478fdfe234f1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="july-2024"&gt;July 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select the Plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I chose a 10x14 full-sun patch of lawn next to the back porch. I deployed a heavy tarp to begin smothering the grass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOA architectural review committee approved the change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soil Testing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take soil samples and send them for analysis to understand nutrient levels and …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="the plot" src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/41ff140f-d3be-435f-98ca-478fdfe234f1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="july-2024"&gt;July 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Select the Plot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I chose a 10x14 full-sun patch of lawn next to the back porch. I deployed a heavy tarp to begin smothering the grass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HOA architectural review committee approved the change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soil Testing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take soil samples and send them for analysis to understand nutrient levels and pH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review results to determine any necessary amendments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="august-2024"&gt;August 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planning and Preparation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalize layout, mark boundaries, install corner posts for trellis wires.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalize vegetables to grow and their planting schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Order seeds and start acquiring plants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="september-2024"&gt;September 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing the Grass:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a layer of compost or mulch to begin enriching the soil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="october-2024"&gt;October 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soil Amendments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin adding organic soil amendments based on soil test results (e.g., lime to adjust pH, compost for nutrients).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="november-2024"&gt;November 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue adding compost to the plot to improve soil structure and fertility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn the soil gently if needed to incorporate organic material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="december-2024"&gt;December 2024&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resting the Soil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow the soil to rest and continue to break down organic matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan any irrigation systems needed for the garden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="january-2025"&gt;January 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tilling and Aerating:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Till the soil to a depth of at least 8-12 inches, breaking up any compacted areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aerate the soil if necessary to improve drainage and root penetration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="february-2025"&gt;February 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Soil Preparation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add a final layer of compost and till it into the soil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level the garden bed and with landscaping rake and create raised rows or mounds depending on plant needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="march-2025"&gt;March 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting Seeds Indoors:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin starting seeds indoors for early crops like tomatoes, peppers, and eggplants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare seed trays and place them in a warm, sunny spot or under grow lights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="april-2025"&gt;April 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planting Early Crops:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As the risk of frost diminishes, begin planting early crops like lettuce, spinach, and peas directly into the garden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harden off indoor-started seedlings by gradually exposing them to outdoor conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="may-2025"&gt;May 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planting Warm-Season Crops:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transplant warm-season crops like tomatoes, peppers, and eggplants into the garden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct sow seeds for squash, beans, and cucumbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="june-2025"&gt;June 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garden Maintenance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mulch around plants to retain moisture and suppress weeds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin regular watering and fertilizing as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trellis?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider installing steel cables between the corner posts as overhead attachment points for suspended plant supports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="july-2025"&gt;July 2025&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harvesting and Care:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue to care for your garden, harvesting crops as they ripen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor for pests and diseases, and manage them organically as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wildlife Deterrents:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider wrapping the corner posts with hardware cloth or chicken wire as a wildlife barrier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Gardening"></category><category term="planning"></category></entry></feed>